Michael Pierce Edenzon

441 Meeting St. Apt. 526, Charleston, SC 29403 edenzonmp@g.cofc.edu | (609) 751-3650

github.com/medenzon linkedin.com/in/medenzon portfolio.michaeledenzon.com

PROFILE STATEMENT

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am a thoughtful and creative individual that draws upon a technical background Class of 2019 Computer Information Systems to find simple solutions to complex problems. My leadership experience and student with industry technical experience in technical skillset augment a proven understanding of strategy and market software development, and leadership experience competition, which allow me to provide exceptional business value in the in both a professional and volunteer capacity, products that I build.

EDUCATION

The College of Charleston – Charleston, SC

2015 - 2019

BS Computer Information Systems

- President & Co-Founder of ProtoX University Prototyping Laboratory (Aug 2016 Present) Assisting students to develop the skills and competencies to invent new products and applications.
 - Responsible for \$50k in assets, \$20k in annual spending, wrote an annual budget
 - Published and executing a five-year strategic plan to grow user base 50% annually
 - Hired and managed 10 student mentors, and a management team of five
 - Created & implemented a re-branding of the School of Business' experiential learning program
 - Secured \$120k for capital expansion and oversaw construction of new facility
- Independent Study of machine learning to algorithmically trade REITs during periods of quantitative tightening
- Peer Mentor in the REACH program for students with intellectual disabilities (Aug 2015 Present)
- Tutor in computer programming and mobile app development (Aug 2015 June 2018)

Relevant Coursework: Computer Programming • Data Structures & Algorithms • Database Concepts

Discrete Mathematics • Statistics • Computer Vision • Video Game Programming Financial & Managerial Accounting • Entrepreneurship & New Venture Modeling

The Hun School of Princeton - Princeton, NJ

2012 - 2015

EXPERIENCE

May 2018 – August 2018

Software Engineering Intern

- Migrated a legacy B2B software application from ColdFusion to C# using .Net Core framework
- Developed a .Net Core web API using DAL/BLL design pattern
- Worked under the Agile (Scrum) methodology

College of Charleston – Department of Computer Science

August 2016 – May 2018

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

- Taught introductory and intermediate computer science concepts in Python
- Held weekly office hours for one-on-one work with students

United States Senate – The Office of Senator Tim Scott

May - June 2016

Intern

- Prepared research for legislation and policy briefings
- Led private tours of The US Capitol, Congressional and Senate offices
- Attended House and Senate hearings to take notes and summarize for legislative staff
- Specialized in calming angry constituents that called the office

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

"Hun Schedule" - iOS app

October 2015

Scheduling app for the Hun School of Princeton – available on the App Store from 2015-2018 More projects & publications available at portfolio.michaeledenzon.com

PRESENTATIONS

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Reforge Summit – November 2016 Charleston, SC Topic: The University Makerspace – *Innovation on college campuses*

Charleston Film Festival – November 2015 Charleston, SC

- C# • SOL
- · Agile/Scrum
- Java · Web API
- · Git, GitHub

- · Swift
- · HTML/CSS
- · Microsoft Excel

- Topic: Virtual Cinematography CGI in low-budget films
- Python · .Net Core
- Windows/Linux/MacOS

PERSONAL

Hobbies: Golf, Squash, Baseball, Guitar, Oil Painting, 3D CAD, App Development, PaddleBoarding, Border Collies